Fear changes everything.
The Mist is a horror, science fiction, thriller film directed by Frank Darabont.
After a violent storm, a dense cloud of mist envelops a small Maine town, trapping David Drayton
and his five-year-old son in a local grocery store with other local residents.
They soon discover that the mist conceals deadly horrors that
threaten their lives, and worse, their sanity.
David Drayton, played by Thomas Jane.
Amanda Dunfrey, played by Laurie Holden.
Ollie Weeks, played by Toby Jones.
Mrs. Carmody, played by Marcia Gay Harden.
Brent Norton, played by Andre Braugher.
Jim, played by William Sadler.
The Mist is a 2007 American horror film produced,
written, and directed by Frank Darabont.
Based on Stephen King's  1980 novella, the film stars an ensemble cast including Thomas
Jane, Marcia Gay Harden, Laurie Holden, Andre Braugher and Toby Jones.
The plot follows a group of people in the small town of Bridgton, Maine, who become trapped inside a
supermarket after a mysterious mist envelops the town, concealing deadly, Lovecraftian creatures.
As fear and paranoia spread, tensions rise among the survivors.
While the film is primarily a monster movie, it explores how
ordinary people react under extreme circumstances.
Darabont notably altered the novella's ending, a change that King praised stating that people who spoil the ending should be “hung by the neck until dead.”
The Mist was filmed in Shreveport, Louisiana, beginning in February 2007,
premiered at ShowEast on October 18, 2007, and was released in the United States on November 21, 2007, by Dimension Films (through Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer), with The Weinstein Company distributing in international markets.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics, and
grossed $57.5 million on a $13–18 million budget.
The film explores themes of monster, based on novel
or book, supermarket, fight, faith.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking and intense.